ANDERS C. RYDEN

500 Broadway St NE, Minneapolis, MN 55413 | 218.349.7641 | rydena021@gmail.com

ryden-rails.herokuapp.com | github.com/rydena021

Technical Skills

Proficient:

- · Ruby on Rails
- MVC Framework, Active Record
- React
- node.js, express.js
- Redux, Redux Sagas
- Python
- AJAX
- · APIs/RESTful web services
- · Database Architecture:
 - MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, MongoDB
- · Command Line Interface:
- Git, RVM
- JavaScript
- iQuery
- HTML5
- · CSS3
- Sass, LESS
- Responsive Design:
 - Twitter Bootstrap, Materialize, Material UI
- Agile
- WordPress
- Sketch
- · MS Office Suite:
 - Word, Excel, PowerPoint, OneNote
- · Apple iWork Suite:
 - Pages, Numbers, Keynote
- · Adobe Suite:
 - Photoshop, Illustrator, Lightroom
- Foreign Languages:
 - Spanish
- eClinicalWorks
- · DataViz Libraries:
- D3.js, dc.js, Crossfilter
- FTP & Web Host Setup:
- Heroku, Sinatra, Middleman
- OAuth 2.0
- RSpec
- · Jest, Supertest
- · Devise
- · Windows OS
- C
- Matlab
- Postman

Summary

Software Engineer bringing lots of enthusiasm and a hunger to learn. Experience with all stages of development for web applications. Familiar with several programming languages and frameworks including Rails, React, SQL, JavaScript, and Python. Strong interest in cybersecurity.

Professional Experience

Solo Project, Tier 4

December 2018 - Current

Designed a web application geared towards Prime graduates to help navigate the job search process. Functionality includes application tracking and contact management.

• Languages/Libraries: React, node.js, express.js, Redux, Redux Sagas, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Material UI, PostgreSQL, Jest, Supertest

Freelance Developer, www.siawso.org

December 2017 - Feb 2018

Planned and executed redesign for nonprofit's website using WordPress and the Avada theme. Responsible for entire scope of project and continuously adapted to client needs.

 Technical skills: WordPress, MAMP local development, SFTP, DNS records, web host migration, WooCommerce, Stripe payment gateway, MailChimp email marketing and automation, Google Analytics, Google Maps API

Project Lead, Le Wagon; Copenhagen, Denmark

February 2017 - March 2017

Created data visualization web app using Donald Trump's Twitter activity. Successfully managed four-person team in development of MVP for end-of-camp pitch presentation.

 Languages/libraries: Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, D3.js, dc.js, Crossfilter, PostgreSQL, Python, Twitter API

Medical Scribe, Duluth Kidney Services; Duluth, MN April 2014 - September 2014

Developed and established scribe program which continually evolved to meet physician's needs. Optimized several processes, reducing physician workload by 2-3 hours per day.

• Job responsibilities included: chart preparation, accompanying physician at patient visits, procedural documentation, lab data entry, and scheduling appointments

Education

Prime Digital Academy; Minneapolis, MN

February 2019

Immersive software engineer program for full stack React development

Le Wagon; Copenhagen, Denmark

March 2017

Coding bootcamp for full stack Rails development

University of St. Thomas; Saint Paul, MN

Spring 2016

Bachelor of Science, Major in Neuroscience